MARTIN METODIEV

+359 (88) 7741192 metodiev.martin@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I was one of those kids who couldn't tell with confidence what they wanted to become when grow up. My answer hit me in my early teens, when I got finished my first web page, developed for Netscape. I felt mighty. I made something out of my hands that was digital and it had value for me back then.

Being in the university I had a great time learning all about graphic designs and digital interfaces. I've earned extensive knowledge of visual arts and gained an eye for beautiful things.

More than 8 years now, I've been professionally involved in building web user interfaces and using contemporary client-side technologies. And my interest increases with every new released UI technology.

As said, by connecting the dots now I realize that getting satisfaction from creating beautiful and friendly web UIs wouldn't be that powerful if it weren't for all those design things I've learned back in the years.

EMPLOYMENT

12/2013 – present SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER Komfo, INC.

Sofia, BG

Take active part in the development and maintenance of the company's Social Media Management platform by developing in-house UI framework and UI components.

technologies & environment: HTML5; CSS3; Less; Sass; Compass; Bootstrap; JavaScript; ¡Query; RequireJS;

> Underscore.is: AngularJS: Grunt: Bower: Git: GitLab: Jenkins: JIRA: JetBrains WebStorm: Sublime Text: Ghostlab 2: Tower 2: Adobe CC

LEAD FRONT-END DEVELOPER 01/2012 - 11/2013

Edamam, LLC Sofia, BG

Taken lead role in the development of the company product's web UI by building it up completely and by making substantive decisions regarding the front-end architecture.

technologies & environment: JSP; HTML5; CSS3; JavaScript; jQuery; Git; JIRA; Panic Coda; Adobe Photoshop

12/2009 - 10/2011

WEB TECHNOLOGIST

BSH, LTD. Sofia, BG

Taken main role in the front-end development of variety of web projects for clients like Armeec, ATrend, Balkan Holidays, BNR, Boyanov & Co., SuperHosting and more.

technologies & environment: (X)HTML; CSS; JavaScript; iQuery; WordPress;

Adobe Dreamweaver / Illustrator / Photoshop

11/2008 - 09/2009

HTML DEVELOPER

Mag Studio, LTD. Sofia, BG

Taken active part in the front-end development of variety of web projects for clients like Bulgarian National Bank, bTV Media Group, Coca-Cola, Kamenitza, Sofica Group and more.

(X)HTML; CSS; SVN; Adobe Dreamweaver / Fireworks / Photoshop technologies & environment:

02/2008 - 09/2008

WEB DESIGNER & HTML DEVELOPER

eDynamo, LLC

Sofia, BG

Handled duties ranging from creative design to code implementation for variety of microsites addressed for the U.S. market.

technologies & environment: (X)HTML; CSS; WordPress; Adobe Dreamweaver / Photoshop

EDUCATION & TRAINING

TRAINING: HOW TO MAKE EASY TO USE WEBSITES

Lucrat Courses

Sofia, BG

A two-day practical training program in approaches and methods for developing usable software products and websites.

course program & topics:

Usability; User needs and requirements; Contextual observation; User profiles; Comparative analysis of competitive products; Information architecture;

Free categorization; Interation design; Usability testing;

Usability testing of mobile devices and more.

2007 – 2009 **GRAPHIC DESIGN** New Bulgarian University Sofia, BG

A two-year minor program that specializes in the study of graphic design, computer creating and image processing.

course program & topics:

Theory and practice of Graphic design; Computer animation (Flash);

Graphical page layout; Visual communication graphics

MULTIMEDIA, COMPUTER GRAPHICS & ANIMATION 2005 – 2009

New Bulgarian University Sofia, BG

A four-year bachelor's program that specializes in the study of multimedia, computer graphics and animation techniques.

course program & topics:

Structures in Programming and Information Technologies; General History of Fine Arts;

Raster Graphics; Vector Graphics; Project in Computer Networks;

Object-Oriented Programming of User Interface; Web Server Management; Creative Web Design; Corporate Design; Animation Techniques and more.

2000 - 2005 **MATHS & INFORMATICS** Mathematical High School Pernik, BG

A five-year high school class of Mathematics and Computer Science with English language.

2000 – 2001 HTML & JAVASCRIPT **Europe Schools**

Pernik, BG

An extracurricular course in HTML4 and JavaScript.

ENGLISH LANGUAGE 1997 – 2003

Europe Schools Pernik, BG

An extracurricular course in English language (level B2).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEVELOPMENT

- ▶ Building-up advanced UI frameworks
- Writing jQuery plugins
- Handling responsive web designs
- Creating fluid grid systems
- Preparing adaptive images
- Developing for mobile devices
- Optimizing styles for print

OUALITY FEATURES

- Developing adaptive architectures
- Testing for cross-browser compatibility
- Complying with standards
- Optimizing for search engines
- Delivering compiled distributions

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

	MAJOR TECHS		FRAMEWORKS & LIBS		PREPROCESS TOOLS
since 2005	(X)HTML(5)	since 2009	jQuery (UI)	since 2013	Less
since 2005	CSS(3)	since 2013	Bootstrap	since 2014	Sass
since 2009	JavaScript —	2014 – 2015	RequireJS —	since 2014	Compass
		2014 – 2015	Handlebars —	since 2015	Jade / Pug 🛑
		2014 – 2015	Underscore —		
		since 2015	AngularJS -		
		since 2016	ReactJS -		
	CMS PRODUCTS		DEV PACKAGES		VCS PACKAGES
since 2008	WordPress	since 2013	npm	since 2012	Git
2008 – 2009	osCommerce	since 2013	Grunt	2008 – 2011	Subversion
		since 2013	Bower		
		since 2014	Yeoman		
	DEV ENVIRONMENT		DOCS ENVIRONMENT		ADOBE SOFTWARE
since 2015	WebStorm	since 2015	Hologram	since 2005	Photoshop
2014 – 2015	Sublime Text	since 2016	SassDoc	since 2009	Illustrator
	Coda	since 2016	Atomic Docs	2008 – 2011	Dreamweaver
2012 – 2014	Coda	311100 2010	7 11011110 2 0 05		
2012 – 2014 since 2014	Tower	since 2013	Markdown syntax		

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Administrative experience (working with colleagues, using administrative software packages)
- ► Teamworking skills (following and/or issuing instructions and contributing to everyday tasks)
- ► Communication and interpersonal skills (working with new people, understanding my assignment)
- Attention to detail through taking accurate messages, researching documents or maintaining records
- Ability to learn quickly and absorb information quickly
- Ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines

REFERENCES

 Victor Penev — former employer, Founder of Netinfo & Edamam 	+1 (646) 378-8317
Boril Karaivanov — former employer, Founder of Redesign.bg	+359 (88) 7564951
► Kalinka Nikiforova — present colleague, UI Designer at Komfo, INC.	+359 (88) 9532319
Lily Grozeva — former colleague, SEO consultant at Allviaweb.com	+359 (89) 4871020
Sia Alexieva — former HTML team lead at Mag Studio, LTD.	+359 (88) 8984200

PORTFOLIO

portfolio.martinmetodiev.com